

VILLU ORAV

software developer

briefly

It was 2005. I went to study Physics. The Time of Science, Technology & Electronics was upon me. Since studies mostly involved programming and development in some form, language, environment, I soon realized that programming languages allow me to express myself. I have been programming for seven years. There have been a variety of different projects: large, small, bloated, lightweight and epic cluster-***

GET IN CONTACT

Kaunase 5-15,50706, Tartu

+372 56 505 812

villu164@qmail.com

S villu.orav

LANGUAGE LEVEL

native

₩ B2

TECHNICAL SKILLS

ruby on Rails i javascript i css java php



TRAITS

- friendly
- ♦ supportive
- positive
- ♦ thorough
- adaptive
- ♦ curious

career

2013 - 2020 WISEMEDIA OÜ ruby developer

Software development, maintenance, support with Ruby on Rails 3.0.9 @ ruby 1.8.7 and migrating to Ruby on Rails 4.2 @ ruby 2.2

ing to Ruby on Rails 4.2 @ ruby 2.3

2012 - 2013 OASIS-SOLUTIONS OÜ web developer

Building webpages on the Wordpress engine

2010 - 2011 Institute of Technology at the UNIVERSITY of

TARTU intern

solo project: electronics & circuits, PHP, JAVA, AviSynth, VirtualDub, C#, PIC, JAL, AtMEGA, C, Li-Po, step-down

2009 - 2010 Computer hardware project course at

UNIVERSITY of TARTU student

building a sound following robot, making an electronic schematic, programming PIC microcontrol-

ler in assembler

education

2009 - ... UNIVERSITY of TARTU, **Physics MSc**

unfinished master's thesis and practical training

2005 - 2009 UNIVERSITY of TARTU, **Physics BSc**

Thesis: "Nanoscale film preparation chamber

design for the surface station."

2002 - 2005 PÄRNU CO-EDUCATIONAL GYMNASIUM

hobbies

I write on demand (for me :D) mini-programs, that simplify and automate tedious tasks.

You can find some examples from here: villu.ga

I love puzzles, ctf (capture-the-flag). My all-time favorite this far is *hacker.org/challenge*